[SINGING] Put down your brains and your entrails.
[CANTANDO] El cerebro tenemos que poner...
It's time to stop and learn some Rails,
para Rails poder aprender,
‘cause we got something new to grab -
hay algo nuevo en la ciudad,
it's Rails for Zombies by Envy Labs.
"Rails para Zombies" de Envy Labs.
You're watching Rails for Zombies,
Están viendo "Rails para zombies",
and this is Level Three, where we're
y en el Nivel 3
going to be talking about Views or the visual representation
hablaremos de "Vistas" o representación visual
of our Rails application.
de nuestra aplicación Rails.
Our Views are where we find our user interface
Nuestras "Vistas" son donde se encuentra la interface de usuario
for our Rails application.
para nuestra aplicación Rails.
And whenever you see Views, you're
Y cada vez que vean "Vistas",
going to be seeing this eyeball; kind of like I'm watching you,
verán este ojo, algo como "te estoy mirando",
which is not really that creepy at all.
que no es tan siniestro.
Maybe a little bit.
Tal vez un poco.
But anyways, it's the visual representation of our app.
Bien, la representación visual de nuestra aplicación.
So once again, here's our user's browser.
Una vez más, aquí está el navegador de usuario.
And they're going to do another request to our Rails app, which
Vamos a hacer otra solicitud a nuestra aplicación Rails,
goes through four different components.
que busca por cuatro diferentes componentes.
Now in the previous level, we talked about Models.
En el nivel anterior hablamos sobre Modelos.
And in this level, we're going to be talking
En este nivel hablaremos
about Views, which sit about here.
sobre "Views" (vistas), que se encuentran aquí.
If we jump into our Rails application,
Si vamos a la aplicación Rails,
zombie_twitter, we're going to find an app folder - remember,
"zombie_twitter", encontraremos una carpeta de aplicación,
that's where our Models were - and we're also
recuerden que allí estaban nuestros Modelos y también
going to find a views folder that gets created for us.
encontraremos una carpeta "Views" creada para nosotros.
Inside there, we're going to create
Adentro, vamos a crear
a zombies folder and a tweets folder.
una carpeta "zombies" y una carpeta "tweets".
Inside tweets, we're going to have an index
Dentro de "tweets" vamos a tener un archivo de índice,
file, index.html.erb, where we're
"index.html.erb",
going to be putting the HTML for listing all of our tweets.
donde pondremos los HTML para la lista de nuestros tweets.
We also have our show.html.erb, which
También tenemos "show.html.erb",
is where we're going to view an individual tweet.
que es donde veremos los tweets individuales.
Now you're probably wondering, I know what HTML is,
Probablemente se preguntarán: "Sé lo que es HTML,
but what's this ERB?
pero ¿qué es ERB?"
Does it stand for Edible Rotting Bodies?
¿Puede ser "Extremidades ricas en betacaroteno""?
No, it doesn't.
No, no es eso.
Big surprise.
Gran sorpresa.
It actually stands for Embedded Ruby.
Realmente quiere decir "Embedded Ruby" (Ruby embebido).
It's our way of embedding Ruby code inside HTML.
Es nuestra manera de embeber el código Ruby dentro de HTML.
Let me show you what that looks like.
Déjenme mostrarles cómo se ve.
The first few we're going to look at
Los primeros que vamos a ver,
is showing an individual tweet.
nos muestran un tweet individual.
So that's inside, views, tweets, show.html.erb.
Dentro de "views/tweets/show.html.erb".
We're going to go ahead and write some boilerplate
Vamos a escribir un texto HTML estándar,
HTML in here, nothing out of the ordinary.
nada extraordinario.
And then we're going to use our tweet model
Y luego utilizaremos nuestro Modelo de tweet
to fetch the tweet with ID of one.
para tomar el tweet con identificación 1.
Notice that less than and greater
¿Ven este signo "menor que" y "mayor que",
than sign with the percentages next to them?
con los porcentajes al lado?
This is how we tell our Rails application
Así le decimos a la aplicación Rails
the code inside here, this is Ruby
que este código es Ruby,
that we want you to execute.
que queremos que lo ejecute.
So we're going to run that code, evaluate that Ruby code,
Vamos a ejecutar el código, evaluar el código Ruby,
and find the tweet with ID of 1.
y encontrar el tweet con identificación 1.
On the next line, we want to print out inside of an h1
En la próxima línea, queremos mostrar dentro de una h1,
the status of the tweet.
el estado del tweet.
Now you notice that there's something a little bit
Se dan cuenta
different with this code.
de que hay algo un poco diferente en este código.
We're using an equal sign.
Estamos utilizando un signo igual.
Putting an equal sign here tells Rails
El signo igual aquí le dice a Rails
that whatever this code inside these tags returns,
que cuando este código dentro de estos tags aparezca de nuevo,
we want it to print out into our HTML.
queremos copiarlo dentro de nuestro HTML.
Lastly, let's print out who posted this tweet.
Por último, copiemos quién posteó este tweet.
So we'll say posted by and then use the brackets again
Diremos: "posteado por", y luego utilizaremos los paréntesis nuevamente
and do tweet.zombie.name.
y escribiremos "tweet.zombie.name".
And if we call this up in the browser,
Si escribimos ésto en el navegador,
we see our tweet status, "Where can I get a good bite to eat?,"
veremos el estado de los tweets "¿Dónde puedo ir a comer algo?,
and see that it was posted by Ash.
y vemos que lo posteó Ash.
From here, if we wanted to go and create another view,
Desde aquí, si quisiéramos crear otra vista,
we would have to take all this HTML
deberíamos tomar todo este HTML,
and copy and paste a lot of the same HTML into it,
y copiar y pegar mucho del mismo HTML en él,
you know a lot of the header stuff
mucho del encabezado,
that's the same on every page.
es lo mismo en cada página.
This isn't very D.R.Y.
No es muy "DRY".
A lot of times in Rails, we'll use the term D.R.Y,
Muchas veces en Rails utilizaremos la sigla "DRY"
D-R-Y. It means Don't Repeat Yourself.
Quiere decir "Dont Repeat Yourself" (no seas repetitivo).
If you ever find yourself writing the same code twice,
Si se ven escribiendo el mismo código dos veces,
there's probably a way to avoid that.
seguramente hay una manera de evitarlo.
And here comes one example.
Aquí hay un ejemplo.
We can take this code and move it out of our view
Podemos sacar este código de vista,
and into a file which is in the views,
y llevarlo a un archivo en "Views",
layouts directory called "application.html.erb."
a un directorio de diseños predeterminados llamado "application.html.erb"
This is created for us with Rails by default,
Lo crea Rails por defecto,
and it's where we put our boilerplate HTML
y es donde ponemos todas nuestras códigos HTML estándar,
code, you know, the headers and the footers and whatnot.
los encabezados y los pies de página, y eso.
Every page we create is going to use this template by default,
Cada página que creamos va a utilizar esta plantilla por defecto,
but there's one problem.
pero hay un problema.
We need to tell our application.html.erb
Debemos decirle a nuestro "application.html.erb"
where to load the code inside of our show view.
donde cargar el código dentro de nuestra vista.
That's where our yield command comes in.
Allí es donde entra nuestro comando "yield" entra en acción.
Yield says this is where the contents
"yield" dice que aquí van los contenidos
of this particular page go, in our case what's
de esta página en particular, en este caso,
inside show.html.erb.
lo que está en "show.html.erb".
So we've D.R.Y.ed up our code.
Hemos aplicado el "DRY" a nuestro código.
But now let's add some allegation to our page.
Pero ahora, agreguemos algo a nuestra página.
How might we make that zombie name into a link,
¿Cómo podemos transformar el nombre del zombie en un link,
so when we click on the zombie name
para que cuando hagamos click en el nombre
it goes to a show zombie page?
nos lleve a la página del zombie?
To create a link inside of our ERB file, the first thing we do
Para crear un link dentro de nuestro archivo erb, lo primero que debemos hacer
is use our percent equal syntax.
es la sintaxis "Porcentaje igual".
Because we want to print this out into the page,
Como queremos copiarlo en la página,
we're going to use a Rails helper method called "link_to."
utilizaremos un método de ayuda de Rails, llamado "link_to".
This will generate a link for us.
Que generará un link para nosotros.
The first parameter we specify for this method
El primer parámetro que especificamos para este método
is the link text.
es el texto del link.
In this case, we want to link text to be the zombie.name.
En este caso, queremos que el texto sea "zombie.name".
Then we specify the URL, except really here we're
Luego especificamos la URL, excepto que aquí
calling a method which returns the URL.
estamos utilizando un método que nos da la URL.
See, Rails comes with a bunch of helpers
¿Ven? Rails viene con un montón de ayudas
which generate URLs for you.
que generan las URL por Uds.
You should never have to hard code URLs.
Nunca deberán copiar las URL.
Here we're calling the zombie_path helper method
Aquí escribimos el método de ayuda "zombie_path"
and sending in the zombie that we want to link to.
e ingresamos el zombie con el que queremos poner el link.
There's actually an alternate syntax for this.
Hay en realidad una sintaxis alternativa para esta tarea.
We can simplify this even more.
Podemos simplificarla aún más.
All we have to do is specify the zombie name
Todo lo que debemos hacer es especificar el nombre del zombie
that we want the link text to be and then send in tweet.zombie.
del que queremos poner el link, y luego ingresar "tweet.zombie".
By default, just by sending in this zombie instance,
Por defecto, solo con enviar, en esta instancia,
Rails knows that we want to go to the show zombie view page.
Rails sabe que queremos ir a la página del zombie.
Here's a link recipe, which you'll need in the challenges.
Aquí está la receta del link, la van a necesitar el los desafíos.
And in case you're wondering which syntax is better to use,
Y en el caso de que se pregunten cuál es la mejor sintaxis para utilizar,
I would go with the shorter one.
yo utilizaría la más corta.
So let's move that link up into our code,
Traslademos el link a nuestro código,
and now if we call it up in our browser,
y si ahora lo escribimos en el navegador,
we can see that Ash is properly linked.
podemos ver el link de Ash.
There's a lot of ways you need to modify HTML links when
Hay muchas maneras para modificar los link HTML
you're building web pages.
cuando están construyendo páginas web.
How might you figure out the options
¿Cómo podemos averiguar las opciones
that you could use with this link_to helper?
para utilizar con esta ayuda "link_to"?
That's a good question.
Esa es una buena pregunta.
Well, Billy, we're glad you asked.
Bueno, Billy, que bueno que preguntaste.
And I don't know why I'm calling you Billy, but I am.
Y no se por qué te estoy llamando "Billy", pero lo hago.
And so we're going to need to look up some documentation
Vamos a necesitar alguna información
to figure out some of these options.
para averiguar algunas de estas opciones.
The first way we could look this up
La primera forma en que podemos hacerlo
is actually by looking in the Rails source code itself.
es realmente buscando en el código fuente de Rails.
So if we didn't have the Rails source, we could download it,
Si no tenemos el código de Rails, podemos descargarlo,
we could go into the Rails directory,
podemos ir al directorio de Rails,
and we could grep for def link_to.
y podemos utilizar "grep" para definir "link_to".
So we would find the function definition,
Entonces podemos encontrar la definición de función,
and above that function, we would actually
y encima de la función
see some pretty good documentation.
veremos bastante información.
Now that's the hard core way of doing it.
Esa es la forma extrema de hacerlo.
Of course, there's documentation that's
Por supuesto, hay información que ya ha sido generada,
already been generated, which we can easily search through
y la podemos encontrar fácilmente en la red,
on the net, for example, going to api.rubyonrails.org, which
por ejemplo, en "api.rubyonrails.org",
always has the latest documentation.
que siempre tiene la información más actualizada.
So if we go there, it looks something like this.
Se ve de esta manera.
And if we type in link_to in the upper left,
Y si escribimos "link_to", arriba a la izquierda,
it will very quickly give us a couple different options.
muy rápidamente nos dará un par de opciones diferentes.
We can click on the first one, since that's what we want.
Podemos hacer click en la primera, porque es la que queremos.
And it will give us some really great documentation as well as
Y nos mostrará muy buena información,
some good examples.
y también muy buenos ejemplos.
If we scroll down on the page, we
Si bajamos en la página,
would see there's this one data attribute called "confirm."
veremos que tiene este atributo llamado "confirm".
And this is just a way that we can add a confirm box.
Y es una forma de agregar una casilla de confirmación.
So let's see what happens when we add that to our link_to.
Veamos que sucede cuando la agregamos a nuestro "link_to".
Here we are back in our show.
Volvemos a nuestro show.
And we're going to specify confirm "Are you sure?"
Y vamos a especificar "confirm: "Are you sure?" (¿está seguro?)
as the last argument.
como último argumento.
And there we go.
Y allí está.
When we go back into our web page and we click that link,
Cuando volvemos a nuestra página web y hacemos click en el link,
we get this nice pop-up that says, "Are you sure?"
nos sale esta ventana que dice: "Are you sure?"
Now let's jump back into our Rails application.
Volvamos a la aplicación Rails.
As we saw in the views directory,
Como vimos en el directorio "views",
there's also a layouts directory.
también hay un directorio "layouts" (diseños).
And inside there, we have our application.html.erb,
Y adentro tenemos nuestro "application.html.erb",
which contains the template for our web page.
que contiene la plantilla para nuestra página web.
We already defined the show.html.erb.
Ya definimos "show.html.erb".
But now let's go ahead and define the index.html.erb.
Ahora definiremos "index.html.erb".
This is where we're going to list out all of our tweets.
Es donde vamos a hacer la lista de todos los tweets.
Here we are inside of our index.html.erb.
Aquí estamos dentro de "index.html.erb".
And the first thing that we want to do is specify a title,
Lo primero que queremos hacer es especificar un título.
Listing tweets.
Listar tweets.
Then we need to create a table.
Luego necesitamos crear una tabla.
The table's going to have two headers, one
La tabla tendrá dos encabezados,
that shows the status and one that
uno que muestra el estado,
shows the zombie that posted this status.
y otro que muestra el zombie que posteó el estado.
Now we need some code that will allow us
Necesitamos un código que nos permita
to loop through every tweet.
enlazar todos los tweets.
Then inside of that loop we're going to print out some things.
Luego, dentro de ese enlace, vamos a copiar algunas cosas.
We're going to print out tweet.status,
Vamos a copiar "tweet.status",
and we're going to print out tweet.zombie.name,
y vamos a copiar "tweet.zombie.name",
the person who created this tweet.
la persona que creó este tweet.
So here comes the code that's going
Este es el código que va a
to allow us to loop through each of the tweets.
permitirnos enlazar cada tweet.
First, we're going to call tweet.all.
Primero, escribimos "tweet.all".
This will return an array of all of the tweets.
Nos dará una lista de todos los tweets.
And then on that array we're going
Y en esa lista,
to be calling dot each do tweet.
vamos a escribir ".each do [ tweet ]".
So this is a code block.
Es un bloque de código.
What's happening here is we're telling
Lo que sucede es que le decimos
our code go through each of the tweets in the array,
al código que vaya por cada uno de los tweets en la lista,
every time setting the current tweet
estableciendo cada vez, cada tweet
to the tweet local variable inside that code block.
a la variable local del tweet dentro de ese bloque de código.
So it goes through the first tweet,
Va por el primer tweet,
sets it, prints it, goes through the second,
lo establece, lo copia, va por el segundo,
goes through the third, and so on, and so forth.
por el tercero, y sigue y sigue.
So let's talk a little bit about what
Hablemos un poco de
each of these items in here return.
cada uno de estos ítems.
Remember, when we call Tweet any place in our Rails app,
Recuerde que cuando escribimos "Tweet" en cualquier lado de nuestra aplicación Rails,
it will reference a class;
va a hacer referencia a una clase;
that class is our model.
esa clase es nuestro modelo.
When we call Tweet.all, we're calling
Cuando escribimos "Tweet.all",
the all method on our tweet model.
estamos escribiendo todo el método en nuestro modelo.
That returns an array of tweets.
Eso nos muestra una lista de tweets.
And then when we call tweet inside of our code block,
Y cuando escribimos "tweet" dentro del bloque de código,
that's going to be a single tweet from that array that
nos va a mostrar un único tweet de la lista
got returned.
que obtuvimos.
And if we call this in on our browser,
Y si escribimos ésto en el navegador,
we can see it properly lists out all of our tweets.
podemos ver que nos da una lista de todos los tweets.
How do you think we would turn each of these values
¿Cómo creen que podemos poner cada uno de estos valores
into links so we could link to the show tweet
en links, para poder vincular con la página de los tweets
page and the show zombie page?
y la página del zombie?
Well, it would look something like this.
Sería algo así.
We would simply call the link_to helper,
Simplemente escribimos la ayuda "link_to",
have the tweet.status as the link text,
tenemos el "tweet.status" como texto del link,
and specify tweet as the second argument, which
y especificamos "tweet" como segundo argumento,
will link us to the show tweet page.
lo que nos vinculará con la página de los tweets.
We just programmed that a minute ago.
Lo programamos hace un minuto.
Then we'll call link_to and specify the zombie.name
Luego escribimos "link_to" y especificamos "zombie.name",
as the link text, and we want that to link
como texto del link, y queremos que nos vincule
to that specific zombie, to show that zombie.
con ese zombie específicamente, para mostrar ese zombie.
Here's a screenshot of what that looks like.
Esta es la pantalla que obtenemos.
This works great.
Funciona perfectamente.
But what if we don't have any tweets yet?
Pero, ¿y si todavía no tenemos ningún tweet?
What if we call up this page and there's none
¿Qué sucede si pedimos esta página y no hay nada,
and there's nothing that says to us that there really is none
y no hay nada que nos diga que no tenemos nada,
and we're left feeling like the page hasn't finished
y parece que la página no se cargó,
loading yet or it's broken?
o no funciona?
How might we change this so that it
¿Cómo podemos hacer que nos muestre
shows no tweets found if there's no tweets?
que no se encontraron tweets si no hay tweets?
Hmm.
Hmn...
Let's figure that out.
Averigûemos eso.
So here we are back with our tweet each loop.
Estamos de vuelta en el rulo "tweet.each".
And to fix this, we're going to pull the Tweet.all out.
Para solucionar el tema, vamos a quitar "Tweet.all".
We're going to set that equal to a variable called tweets.
Vamos a ponerlo con una variable llamada "tweets".
Then we're going to call tweets.each,
Luego escribimos "tweet.each",
and it's going to go through that array.
y va a ir por la lista.
We'll say if tweets.size equals 0,
Decimos que "if tweets.size" es igual a 0,
and then we'll specify what to print out if it is 0.
y especificamos que lo copie si es igual a 0.
And then we'll end that conditional.
Y terminamos esa condición.
So only if that conditional is true will
Sólo si esa condición es verdadera,
it print out what's in between the if in the end.
copiará lo que está entre el "if" y el final.
And if we jump back into our browser,
Volvemos al navegador,
we see that it now prints out, "No Tweets Found."
y vemos que ahora dice: "No Tweets found" (no se encontraron tweets).
Sometimes our zombies might change their mind,
Puede ser que nuestros zombies cambien de idea,
and they might want to edit their tweets
y que quieran editar los tweets,
or delete their tweets.
o borrarlos.
So how might we add links right here
¿Cómo podemos agregar un link aquí mismo
that would allow them to do that or get them one step closer?
que permita hacerlo o llegar más cerca?
To do an edit link in Rails, it looks something like this.
Un link de edición en Rails es más o menos así.
We say link_to, specify Edit.
Decimos "link_to", especificamos "Edit".
And then to generate the right URL, we write edit_tweet_path
Y para generar la URL correcta, escribimos "edit_tweet_path",
and then send in the tweet.
e ingresamos el tweet.
Then to create a delete link, we do link_to Destroy.
Para crear un link para borrar, escribimos "link_ to Destroy".
We send in the tweet that we want to delete and then specify
Ingresamos el tweet que queremos borrar,
method delete.
y especificamos "method: :delete"
These URL generators may feel a little weird in the syntax,
La sintaxis de estos generadores de URL puede parecer extraña,
but don't worry.
pero no se preocupen.
There is a method to the madness.
Hay un método en la locura.
Also, this is the first time that we've
Es la primera vez
seen a hash where we have a symbol as a key which
que vemos un hash donde hay un símbolo como clave,
links to another symbol as a value.
que vincula con otro símbolo como valor.
That's why we have those two colons there.
Por eso tenemos esos dos puntos allí.
And if we call up the web page, we
Y si escribimos la página web,
can see that we have a bunch of links now.
vemos que tenemos un grupo de links.
Let's take a look at all of those URLs generators
Veamos esos generadores de URL,
and what the URL is that they generate.
y lo que va a generar la URL.
So first up, to list all the tweets basically go
Primero, para listar todos los tweets, básicamente vamos
to our index action that we just created.
a la acción index que recién creamos.
We use the code tweet_path.
Utilizamos el código "tweet_path".
The URL this generates is slash tweets.
La URL que genera es "/tweets".
To get a new tweet form, typically in Rails,
Para obtener una nueva forma de tweets, generalmente en Rails,
we use the code new_tweet_path to generate
utilizamos el código "new_tweet_path" para generar
the URL slash tweets slash new.
la URL "/tweets/new".
The following URL generators need a specific tweet
Los siguientes generadores de URL necesitan un tweet específico
to send in as an argument.
para ingresar como argumento.
So the first one here is to show a tweet.
El primero es mostrar un tweet.
We saw this before.
Ya lo vimos.
And we just send in the tweet instance itself,
E ingresamos la instancia de tweet,
and it generates a URL, which has slash tweet slash 1.
y genera una URL, que tiene "/tweet/1".
Then to edit a tweet, we use edit_tweet_path tweets,
Para editar un tweet, utilizamos "edit_tweet_path(tweet),
which generates a URL, which looks like this.
que genera una URL que se ve así.
And then to delete a tweet, we use this code,
Y para borrar un tweet, utilizamos este código,
which generates a URL like this.
que genera una URL así.
And as I mentioned, this code column, those
Como dije antes, esta columna de código,
are the URL generators.
esos son lo generadores de URL.
And those all go in our link_to as the second argument.
Y todos ellos van en nuestro "link_to" como segundo argumento.
I'm sure your zombie brain is full of syntax at this point,
Estoy seguro de que sus cerebros zombies están llenos de sintaxis en este momento,
so why don't you stumble on over to the challenges.
así que ¿porqué no se dan una vuelta por los desafíos?